Mss.Ms.Coll.115
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Robert Patterson Kane, 1830-1905; This collection includes letters, letterbooks (1853-1860, legal matters), notebooks on legal cases. Much of this relates to Kane's legal practice in Philadelphia with his father, J. K. Kane, but there is also family correspondence, and much that relate
  - Letterbook #7, 1858-1860
    - Holbrook, J., 1858 December 7
    - Hollister, William H., 1858 December 24
    - Huntington, J.M. and Company, 1858-1859
    - Husbands, C.M., 1858 December 7
    - Ingham, William, 1859 March 2
    - James, John F., 1858 March 9
    - Jeffrey, William, 1859 January 19
    - Johnson, F. and J.W., 1858
    - Kane, J.D.L., Undated
    - Kane, J.K., Jr., 1858 September 2
    - Keller, Charles M., 1859 October 18
    - Koffman, Sydney, 1858
    - Leiper, George G., 1859 September 12
    - Leiper, Mrs. M.B., 1858 April 30
    - Loyd, William, 1859 March 1
    - Martin, J. Hill, 1859 December 6
    - Martin, Ward, 1860 January 19
    - McAllister, Wardale G., 1859 January 17
    - McCall, Peter, 1859 October 7
    - McCracken, Henry F., 1860 February 1
    - McHenry, George, 1859 October 28
    - McMurtrie, R.C., Undated
    - Middleton, D.W., 1859 November 9
    - Morris, Henry W., 1858 April 17
    - Morton, Mrs., 1859
    - Moses, L.M., 1858
    - Moss, E.A., 1859 September 28
    - Muller, Andrew, 1859 December 13
    - Neal, Charles M., 1858 November 4
    - Pasper, Alex, 1858
    - Patents, Commission of, 1859 July 18
    - Patterson, Aunt, Undated
    - Patterson, R., 1858 September 25
    - Pearson, Jno M., 1858 April 15
    - Penrose and Burton, 1858 August 13
    - Phillips, B., 1859
    - Phillips, Henry M., 1859 March
    - Pleasants, Samuel, 1859
    - Pratt, E.B., 1858-1859
    - Randall, Robert, 1858 April 7
    - Raven and Bradley, 1858 April 12
    - Redding, A.W., 1858 September 24
    - Reed, Mrs., 1859 March 4
    - Rhoads and Son, 1859 July 5
    - Robertson, H., 1858 March 13
    - Rush, J. Murray, 1859
    - Russell, A.E., 1859
    - Sabine, A., Undated
    - Sampson and Tappan, 1858-1859
    - Scott, R. Robinson, 1859 September 19
    - Scudder and Randall, 1858 September 20
    - Serrill, J.I., 1858 October 4
    - Sheppard, Thurman, 1858 July 8
    - Smith, Audrey H., 1858 July 14
    - Smith, Mary R.G., 1859 September 28
    - Smith, Thomas D., 1859 August
    - Smith, William, 1859 March 30
    - Smucker, Samuel M., 1859 November 1
    - Snyder, Jacob, 1858 May 27
    - Sonder, E.A. and Company, 1858
    - Spencer, J.A., 1858 October 4
    - Starr, F.R., 1859 January 25
    - Stetson, D.S. and Company, 1858
    - Struthers, T., 1858 March 21
    - Sutton, D.S., 1858
    - Swaby, Jno H., 1858 November 4
    - Taylor, John, 1859 May 6
    - Thomas, Aunt, Undated
    - Thomas, Evan W., 1859-1860
    - Thomas, Jno H., 1859
    - Thorp, S.S. and J.O., 1859
    - Tingley, C., 1858 June 17
    - Van Dyke, F.A. and Company, 1859
    - Van Dyke, J.C., 1858-1859
    - Van Gilder, Thomas, 1858
    - Walthall, W., 1859 May 6
    - Watts, H.M., 1858 August 29
    - Webster, J., 1858 November 4
    - Wendell, J.S., 1859 January 22
    - Wharton, G.M., 1858-1860
    - Wharton, H., 1858
    - Wickham, John, 1858 April 14
    - Williams, Duane, 1859 March 9
    - Wools, Jacob, 1858 March 22
    - Young, E.R., 1859 July 22
- Series IV. Thomas Leiper Kane, 1840-1878; These letters and documents relate primarily to family matters, mostly for the 1850-1860 period, but there is material pertaining to Kane's expedition to Utah to help avert war between the Mormons and the United States. There is also a portion of the manuscript of his book, "The Mormons," published in 1850.; Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1822-1883
  Thomas Leiper Kane (1822-1883, APS, 1856) was a lawyer, soldier, philanthropist, entrepreneur and defender of the Mormons. Kane was born in Philadelphia, the son of jurist and politician John Kintzing Kane and his wife Jane Duval Leiper. Kane attended school in Philadelphia, and later traveled abroad to Britain and France to study and visit relatives. He was small in stature, never robust and struggled with ill health for most of his life. While in Paris he served as an attaché of the American legation. In France he met the French philosopher and sociologist Auguste Comte, who encouraged his social conscience and involvement with philanthropic causes. Kane returned home to the United States in 1844 to read law in the firm of his father Judge John Kintzing Kane, and was admitted to the bar in 1846. One of Thomas Leiper Kane’s most important associations was with the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, the Mormons, a group he supported politically, and whose leader Brigham Young he befriended. He helped to recruit members of the Mormon Battalion in the Mexican War and assisted them in getting postal service established in their settlements. Kane was an active abolitionist, and was appointed the chairman of the Pennsylvania Free Soil State Central Committee in 1848. Two years later in 1850 he resigned as a U.S. district commissioner in Protest of the Federal Fugitive Slave Act. A close friend of newspaper publisher Horace Greeley, Thomas Leiper Kane later joined the Free Soil Movement and worked with the underground railroad in the 1850s. At the beginning of the Civil War in 1861 Kane organized a volunteer regiment, the 13th Pennsylvania Reserves, also known as the Kane Rifles. He was commissioned a lieutenant colonel, and took part in battles at Dranesville, Virginia and Harrisonburg in the Shenandoah Valley. Captured in June, 1862, he was released a short time afterward in a prisoner exchange, but went on to fight at Chancellorsville in May 1863 and Gettysburg in July, 1863. Battle wounds and ill health eventually led to Kane’s resignation from the Union Army in November, 1863. Later he was promoted to the rank of major general for his valor at Gettysburg. Following the Civil War Kane was closely involved with the McKean and Elk Land Improvement Company, of which he was the primary organizer. He was also the organizer of the New York, Lake Erie and Western Coal Company, and the prime mover behind the 2,053-foot Kinzua viaduct, then considered the largest railroad bridge in the world. He also was active in philanthropic and cultural endeavors, becoming the first president of the Pennsylvania Board of State Charities and a member of the American Philosophical Society in 1856. In 1869 Kane unsuccessfully lobbied the Grant Administration to become governor of the Utah Territory. Kane joined his friend Brigham Young to found several Mormon colleges, one of which was the Brigham Young Academy (later Brigham Young University). Despite his long and close association with the Mormons, Kane never joined the LDS church. He requested that his heart be buried in Salt Lake City, but was interred in the family chapel in Kane, Pennsylvania.
  Early American History note This is a relatively small collection of documents from Thomas Leiper Kane, a member of the prominent Philadelphian Kane family. Among the notable items is an account Kane wrote of his interactions with a Mormon community in the western United States. Much of the correspondence and other documentation (business and personal finance) are from the 1850s and beyond.
  Presented by Mrs. Joseph Aub, Oliver Cope, Thomas Pym Cope, and Mrs. Thomas P. Hazard, children of Walter Cope and Eliza Middleton Kane Cope. Accessioned, 1970 (1970 146ms).
  Cain family.; Heazlett, Charles T.; Ingersoll, Joseph R. (Joseph Reed), 1786-1868; Kane, Elizabeth Wood, 1836-1909; Kane, Jane Duval Leiper; Kane, John K. (John Kintzing), 1795-1858; Kane, Robert Patterson, 1827-1906; Peale, Franklin, 1795-1870; Taylor, Robert; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841; General Correspondence; Manuscripts (for publication).; Mormons -- Utah -- History.; Nauvoo (Ill.) -- Expulsion of the Mormons.; Philadelphia (Pa.) -- Social life and customs.; Religion
  - Papers
    - Albright, C., 1854 July 24
    - American Philosophical Society Wistar Party, 1849-1851
    - Bernhisel, John M., 1852 January
    - Bills for E.K. Kane estate, 1857
    - Bills, receipts, etc., 1852-1858
    - Bliss, B. W. and Company, 1871 May 15
    - Channing, W.H., 1850 July 22
    - Chicago Gas, Light and Coke Company, 1857 February 16
    - Chicago Gas, Light and Coke Company, 1857 September 7
      To C.F. Heazlett.
    - Crouch, Thomas and Richard, 1852 February 20
    - Delphian Cricket Club, 1858
    - Descendents...
    - Dunlap, Mrs., Undated
    - Elliott, Charles W., 1857 August 30
    - Erwin, Ellen C., 1851 December 3
    - Forney, John W., 1852 January 6
    - Girard Life Insurance Company, 1855 February
    - Glidden, William T., 1840 February 11
      To Mrs. Desmond.
    - Heazlitt, Charles T., 1850, 1857-1858
    - Ingersoll, J. R., 1852 February 16
    - Kane, Elizabeth, 1857 July 24
    - Kane, Mrs. Elizabeth D., 1857-1865
    - Kane, Mrs. Jane Duval Leiper, 1853 March 16
      To Louisa Kane.
    - Kane, John Kintzing, Jr., 1857 November 23
    - Kane, John Kintzing, Jr., 1857
    - Kane, Robert Patterson, Undated
    - Kane, Mrs. R. P., 1862 November 25
      To C.A. Dana.
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, Undated
      Concerning the Mormons...
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, Undated
      Concerning the Mormons and President Buchanan...
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1841 January 16
      To E.K. Kane.
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1849-1865
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1846, 1859
      To R.P. Kane.
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, Undated
      To R.P. Kane, in regard to Mormons.
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1878 August 6
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1858 February
      Letter to _____
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1849-1850
      "The Mormons"-original draft.
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1852 February 21
      Notice of Elisha's lecture.
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, Undated
      Postscript to the second edition, regarding the Mormons.
    - Kane, Thomas Leiper, Undated
      Report, copied for Gov. A. Cumming.
    - Lewis, W.D., Undated
    - Mercer, S.A., Undated
    - Merrick and Son, 1851-1852
    - Osborne, A., 1858 April 19
      To R.P. Kane, with newspaper clippings.
    - Peale, Benjamin Franklin, 1840 January 4
      To Joseph Houston.
    - Pennsylvania Company for Insurances, 1855 February 15
    - Philadelphia Citizens, 1852
      Aid to Hungary.
    - Sedgwick, Theodore, 1850 July 11
    - Struthers, T., 1857 April 11
    - Vaughan, John, 1840 January 4
      To Robert Layton.
    - Welsh, Henry, 1852 January 14
    - Western Bank check book, 1857
    - Wilcox, A.J., 1857 August 8
      Deed.
    - Wood, William, 1850 March 15
    - Wood, William, 1863 June 30
      To Mrs. T.L. Kane.
- Series V. Francis Fisher Kane, 1880-1955; Francis Fisher Kane (1866-1955) was a Philadelphia lawyer and U.S. Attorney for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania, 1913-1920. This collection of letters, reports, briefs, and documents, reflects Kane's politically liberal interests in Indian rights, prison reform, public defenders, and numerous other judicial reforms. There is much family and personal correspondence in the collection. Of particular note is the material concerning the case of the United States vs. Kurt Molzahn, a Philadelphia pastor accused of espionage as a German spy in 1942. This collection documents, as well, Kane's early education at St. Paul's School, Concord, NH and at Princeton University. There is significant or voluminous correspondence with the American Friends Service Committee, on Italian/American trade ca.1915 (in the Eduardo Giretti correspondence), with the Indian Rights Association, the Philadelphia Prison Society, and the Philadelphia Voluntary Defender Association.; Kane, Francis Fisher, 1866-1955
  Presented Dr. and Mrs. Oliver Cope, youngest child of Walter Cope and Eliza Middleton Kane Cope. Accessioned, 11/10/1978 (1978 1671ms). Materials acquired from the Rhode Island Historical Society are noted.
  A Philadelphia lawyer, Francis Fisher Kane, was active throughout his life in criminal justice reform, and the defense of civil liberties and equality before the law for minorities and the poor. Kane was born in Philadelphia on June 17, 1866, the son of Robert Patterson Kane (1827-1906), an admiralty, patent lawyer and active Democrat, and Elizabeth Francis Fisher (1840-1919). He was the grandson of John Kintzing Kane(1795-1858) a distinguished jurist and Judge of the Eastern District Court of Pennsylvania. Francis Fisher Kane received his secondary education at St. Paul's School, an Episcopalian boarding school in Concord, NH. He graduated from the College of New Jersey (now Princeton University), class of 1886, where he won the Lyman K. Arwater prize in political science. He was admitted to the Pennsylvania Bar in 1889 after receiving his law degree at the University of Pennsylvania and was in private practice until appointed First Assistant United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania in 1896. He served in this position until 1900. Appointed by Woodrow Wilson in 1913 as the U.S. Attorney for the Eastern District, he served in this capacity until 1920, when at the age of 53 he resigned in protest over mass arrests authorized by the U.S. Attorney General A. Mitchell Palmer in a government drive against Communists. In August 1891 the Indian Rights Association sent Kane and Philadelphia lawyer Frank M. Riter, to Colorado and Utah to report on the situation of the Southern Utes and the U.S. government's proposal to relocate them from their reservation in southern Colorado to Utah, a plan which was successfully opposed. Kane had previously traveled West to Montana with the Princeton Scientific Expedition of 1886, led by William Berryman Scott and Francis Speir, in search of fossils. His early interest in politics led to unsuccessful Democratic nominations for the Pennsylvania House of Representatives (1890) and for mayor of Philadelphia in 1903. Upon joining the Pennsylvania Prison Society in 1926, as a member of its Acting Committee, he organized support on behalf of establishing a public defender in Philadelphia. While President of the Prison Society he helped to establish the Citizens' Committee for a House of Detention for Adult Untried Defendants in Philadelphia. In 1935, Kane received the Philadelphia Award for his successful work with the Society. In addition, Kane was senior council in the espionage case during World War II of the United States vs. Kurt E.B. Molzahn, a German-born Lutheran pastor living in Philadelphia, From 1951-1952, he continued to work as a defender of the disenfranchised with the case of Edward Way, a Philadelphia black man convicted of the murder of a white man in South Carolina. At the age of 86, Kane was honored with the degree of Doctor of Humane Letters by Temple University. He died on May 27, 1955 in Belmont Massachusetts.
  See also Series VIII, IX.
  American Friends Service Committee.; Cadwalader, Sophia Francis; Cain family.; Cope, Eliza Middleton Kane, 1863-1952; Devries, William Levering; Dow, Margaret Elder; Giretti, Edoardo, b. 1864; Indian Rights Association.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857; Kane, Elizabeth Francis Fisher; Kane, John K. (John Kintzing), 1795-1858; Kane, Robert Patterson, 1827-1906; Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1822-1883; Molzhan, Kurt -- Trials, litigation, etc.; Pennsylvania Prison Society.; Philadelphia Voluntary Defender Association.; Princeton University.; Shields, James K.; St. Paul's School (Concord, N.H.); Walnut, T. Henry; Wanamaker, John, 1838-1922; Wanamaker, Rodman, 1863-1928; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; Briefs.; Indians of North America--Legal status, laws, etc.; Italy -- Commerce.; Lawyers.; Philadelphia (Pa.) -- Social life and customs.; Prison reformers -- United States.; Prisons -- Pennsylvania.; Reports.; Social reformers -- United States.; Trials (Espionage) -- United States.; United States -- Commerce.; Ute Indians; Ute Indians--Removal
  - Papers, 1856-1952; 4.0 lin. feet
    - A, 1915-1924
      Acquired from the Rhode Island Historical Society.
    - Academy of Natural Sciences, 1922
    - Accounts, 1892 January 26
      Signed "Robt."
    - Adams, Lida Stokes, 1922
      Re: Philadelphia League of Women Voters talk.
    - Albright, Horace M., 1922
    - American Association for Labor Legislation, 1914-1919
    - American Bar Association Journal, 1922 March
      Edgar B. Tolman.
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1922-1923, 1949-1950
      Correspondence and printed material.
    - American Committee for Protection of the Foreign Born, 1948-1952
      Form letters.
    - American Friends Service Committee #1, 1920-1922
      White Slave Law; Russia.
    - American Friends Service Committee #2, 1943 April-July
      Samuel R. Lengyel case.
    - American Friends Service Committee #3, 1943 August-1944
    - American Friends Service Committee #4, 1945-1946
    - American Friends Service Committee #5, 1950-1951
      1 Lengyel item, minutes, receipts.
    - American Ice Company, 1922 December
    - American Institute of Architects #1, 1907-1909
    - American Institute of Architects #2, 1910-1913
    - American Institute of Architects #3, 1914
    - American Red Cross, 1917-1920
    - American Social Hygiene Association, 1922
    - American Union Against Militarism, 1919
      Extracts of Testimony of Archibald E. Stevenson.
    - Anderson, Elizabeth, 1920-1923
      School teaching and reformers.
    - Anderson, Mary V., 1916-1919
    - Andrade, Jacob A.P.M., 1919
    - Arthur, James, 1916-1918
    - Ashman, William, 1906
      Legal Aid Society.
    - Aub, Elizabeth, 1930 January 11
      His greatniece.
    - Aub, Joseph C., 1940 April 17
      His greatnephew.
    - Audi, Adele, 1923
    - Autobiography of Judge John K. Kane, 1917, 1942-1950
    - Autographs, 1911-1912
      Correspondence in this file were acquired from the Rhode Island Historical Society.
      Signature cards of Grover Cleveland, John Fisher, Caeser Rodney, Charles J. Guiteau (assassin of President Garfield). Also, correspondence with the Mayor of Philadelphia and personal letters from Woodrow Wilson while Governor of New Jersey.
    - B, 1892-1924
    - Baker, Newton D., 1918
      United States Secretary of War.
    - Baker, Ray Stannard, 1928
      Regarding Woodrow Wilson (8p.)
    - Ballard, Frances Anne, 1921
      Her application to the New York Bar Association.
    - Bank of North America and Trust Company, 1924
    - Barringer, Philip, 1949-1950
      His nephew; working in Defense Department.
    - Bartlett tours, 1920
    - Baugh, B.A., 1921 August 12
      Dinner on B&O Railroad.
    - Beck, James M., 1896 December 9
      U.S. Attorney, to R.P. Kane regarding son F.F.K.'s legal performance and abilites.
    - Beckford, W.H., 1915
    - Beeber, D., 1906 June 23
      Thanks for marriage congratulations.
    - Beitler, Abraham M., 1906, 1909
      Legal.
    - Bell, C.M.E., 1932-1946
    - Bell, John Cromwell, 1905, 1909
      Legal; mentions Wallerstein.
    - Bell Telephone Company, 1917-1923
    - Bent, Silas, 1878
      Address before Academy of Sciences.
    - Berry, William H., 1906, 1907
      Pennsylvania State Treasurer.
    - Betts, Margaret, 1922
    - Biddle, Alice, 1922
    - Biddle, Edward M., 1920
    - Biddle, Francis B., 1921
      Regarding Miss Thayer's proposal.
    - Biddle, Owen, 1950 March 2
      Mentions A.H. MacCormick, Prison Society, Shakespeare Society.
    - Bispham, G. Tucker, 1922
    - Black, J.S., 1906 October 4
      Democratic candidate.
    - Blair, D.H., 1921
      IRS commissioner; F.F.K. recommends Charles V. Mallet for employment.
    - Blake, Edmund M., 1920
    - Bockius, Frances M. #1, 1906
    - Bockius, Frances M. #2, 1907-1908
    - Bockius, Frances M. #3, 1909-1910
    - Bockius, Frances M. #4, 1911
    - Bockius, Frances M. #5, 1912
    - Bockius, Frances M. #6, 1913-1920
    - Bonaparte, Charles J., 1907 June 4
      U.S. Attorney General; F.F.K. wrote to him regarding Thomas Marple.
    - Bright, Robert S., 1915-1922
    - Brooks, N.C., 1921 October 25
      Philadelphia whiskey scandal.
    - Brooks, Phillips, 1888 June 26
      Letter of regret to William Levering Devries.
    - Brookwood Worker's College, Katonah, N.Y.
      Correspondence with A.J. Muste.
    - Brown, Francis Shunk, 1922
      Regarding Lawyer's Club and Spanish Consul.
    - Brown, James Crosby, 1919-1922
      Regarding Welfare Federation.
    - Browne, Jean Kane Foulke, 1922
      His cousin.
    - Bud, Florence, 1949 December 16
    - Burks, Jesse D., 1917
    - Burnham, George, Jr., 1914-1918
    - Burnham, Lewis, 1921 October 12
      Visit to Mr. MacCoy's office.
    - Burns Detective Agency, 1921
      Concerning a recommendation for Charles V. Mallet.
    - Butler, William, 1899 January 27
      Friendly letter.
    - C, 1915-1923, 1949
    - Cadbury, Emma, 1944 April 3
      Regarding Lengyel case.
    - Cadwalader, John, 1903-1922
      His uncle; pertaining business.
    - Cadwalader, Sophia Francis #1, Undated
    - Cadwalader, Sophia Francis #2, Undated
    - Cadwalader, Sophia Francis #3, Undated
    - Calhoun, Thomas B., 1921-1922
      Plea for help from homeless drug addict.
    - Calling cards, Undated
      Various.
    - Cameron, A.G., 1885 July 15
    - Capital Punishment, 1930
      Newspaper clippings and printed material.
    - Carsill, May, August 13
      Thanks him for music sent; mentions family and mutual acquaintances.
    - Carson, Hampton L., 1906, 1918
      1906 January 13--Arrangements for meeting with Mr. Fels. 1908 December 30--Letter of introduction for F.F. Kane, Florence Kane, and Miss Moss to Lloyd Garrison, U.S. Ambassador to Italy.
    - Chantland, William B., 1921
      Regarding Landis case.
    - Chestnut Street Association, 1921 December 8
      Regarding idea for improving Chestnut Street.
    - Chew, Mary, 1903-1904, 1919
      To Lila Kane.
    - Chew, Samuel, 1920
    - Chicago Crime Commission, 1921 November 21
      From Henry Barrett Chamberlin; placing on mailing list.
    - Chisolm, William Garnett, Undated
      Sends copy of Mrs. Reid's "Life of Thayer". Mentions Mrs. Mercer and "our mutual cousins".
    - Christy, Bayard H., 1921 December 18
      Mentions Mrs. Cope.
    - Chuat, Itzke, 1921
    - The Churchmen, 1919-1924
      Regarding article on Christian view of war.
    - Citizens Committee for House of Detention #1, 1944-1949
    - Citizens Committee for House of Detention #2, 1949-1950
    - Citizens Committee for House of Detention #3, 1951
    - Citizens Committee for House of Detention-Correspondence #1, 1949 March
    - Citizens Committee for House of Detention-Correspondence #2, 1949 April-May
    - Citizens Committee for House of Detention-Correspondence #3, 1949 June-July
    - Citizens Committee for House of Detention-Correspondence #4, 1951
    - Citizens Conference on International Economic Union, 1948 February 24
      F.F. Kane to act as their representative at Conference on Human Rights and Freedom of Information.
    - City Club of Philadelphia, 1915-1921
      Asking for bond subscribers.
    - City (Philadelphia) vs. Durham et al, 1906 December 17
      From E. Spencer Miller regarding lawsuit.
    - Civil Rights Congress, 1950 October 24
      Regarding the McCarren Law.
    - Clark, B., Undated
      Schoolboy letter.
    - Cleghorn, Sarah, 1920, 1949-1952
      To F.F. Kane and Eliza Kane Cope.
    - Cobb, Charles Kane, 1940 March 4
      Distant relation seeking genealogical information.
    - Coit, Henry A., 1882, 1887, 1889
      Rector of St. Paul's School.
    - Coles, L.F., 1921-1922
      Requesting money for Friends of Negro Freedom.
    - Commission on Commitments and Detention, 1951
      Report; also acts of 1945 and 1917.
    - Commission on the Church and Social Service, 1922
      Concerning the Mooney Case and the character of Francis R. Welsh.
    - Committee of 100, 1950